uh
[Music]
down
so
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen
good day and welcome to the q4 fy 2022
earnings conference call of angel one
limited
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the lesson only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing start and see on
your touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
this conference call may contain
forward-looking statements about the
company which are based on the beliefs
opinions and expectations of the company
as on date of this call
these statements are not the guarantees
of future performance and involve risk
and uncertainties that are difficult to
predict
i now hand the conference over to mr
little goodka
thank you and over to you sir
good morning everyone
on behalf of angel one limited i would
like to welcome all of you to our q4f520
earnings call
i am richard burka head of invest
relations at angel one
today we have on the call
mr dinesh tucker chairman managing
director narayan gander chief executive
officer ini raghaval
dr pravin bhatte
chief legal and compliance officer
subhash manan chief human resources
officer
bhavin parikh
head of operations risk and surveillance
devendra kumar
head of online revenue
lga or ir consultants
we have published a detailed investor
presentation and issued a press release
to the stock exchanges highlighting our
performance for quarter four and for for
the full year 2022.
i hope you have had a chance to look at
it
with this brief introduction i now
invite denis tucker to give a opening
remarks
for the user
thank you ethan good morning everyone
the recently concluded financial year
2022 has been a landmark year for the
brokering industry
as of march this year the country had
nearly 90 million demand accounts
representing about 18 percent of kiger
over the past 20 years
despite multiple headwinds on the way
most of this growth has come over the
past five years
during which industry has grown at
approximately 30 percent of kaggar
this has been a result of massive
changes in ecosystem
along with significant reforms within
the industry
both from regulators as well as the
participants
leading the macro transformation within
the ecosystem has been a completely
overhauled internet infrastructure
access to affordable smart and feature
phones
lower data charges rising financial
literacy
expanding income levels the digitization
of various services
and the bargaining desire
from the younger generation to own
equities as an asset class
the emergence of fintech players and the
dynamic changes they brought to the
economy were largely responsible for the
rapid transformation of financial
landscapes
this place leverage their digital
progress and capacity to innovate
for innovation to build apps that would
expand their reach and enable them to
seamlessly offer a wide variety of
financial products to a significantly
large and different market
coupled with this a plethora of recent
regulations and the development of large
digital repositories ensured the safe
keeping of personal data
and motivated investors to upskill their
awareness of financial products and
actively perceive investment in indian
markets
the
meteoric of a growth of
broken industry in fact 2022
set a new record in terms of investors
participation
for example india added nearly 35
million new gmat account
representing
a year-on-year growth of around 63
percent
on an incremental basis india opened 2.4
times more deemed accounts in afi 2022
than fi 2021
this led to a steady improvement in
equity penetration which today stands at
about
6.4 percentage compared to over four
percentage last year
however even at this level we are far
from far behind our global peers
furthermore fr 2022 have been the best
year in terms of average daily turnover
for entire industry
a dto on nsc drew 2.6 times in fact 2022
to increase 69 trillion from rupees 27
trillion last year
this growth has been fueled by
increasing retail participation
the share of the retail investor in cash
segment of the nsa store that 41 percent
in fi 2022 compared to 33 percent in fi
2016.
direct investments for retail investors
in cash segment of msc in africa 2022
have been stronger with net inflows in
10 out of 11 months
amounting to approximately rupees 2
trillion
this is nearly 2.5x of the inflows
during the same period last year
all this reflects the changing behavior
of retail investors in india
today they have a better understanding
of significance of financial fitness
unlike their old older cohorts the
newest individuals value the potential
of the handsome returns from equity
in spite of unpredictability of current
global economy
with significantly reduced return on a
low risk asset equity are strongly
emerging as a natural choice of
sustainable investments
the united kingdom had a similar
experience between
and 1992
when inflation interest rate fell by 40
to 50 percent
during this period the percentage of
households investing in stocks and
shares increased threefold to 25
this phenomenon is being replicated in
india and over the next decade i expect
we will achieve 25 to 30 percent
penetration
with all industry statistics
progressively leaning towards media
digital businesses a significant segment
of the businesses including incremental
clients and volumes is turning to those
innovation driven intermediaries
the cornerstone of growth in the
investment domain is pioneering
technology accompanied by reliable and
relatable content that can be seamlessly
integrated by new users who account for
a large slice of market buy
both in terms of limit account and
active clients
we are already witnessing this trend
as the top five digital brokers today
account for approximately 58 percent of
the total active client on the msc
compared to approximately
12 percent in fact 2018.
this digital business accounted for
about 70 percent of the market share of
incremental elective clients on nfc in
fy 2022 compared to 24 percent in fi
2018.
angel has been able to garner a fair
share of this tech led growth to its
digital business in the past few years
our endeavor to offer our client the
best investing experience is we think
this residence as evidenced by our
continuously improving operational
performance over the past few quarters
i am happy to share with you that angel
one command 10 plus market share of
india's total as well as active demand
accounts our emphasis on deploying
advanced analytical capabilities based
on data science artificial intelligence
and machine learning across our
acquisition and engagement in games is
helping us to continuously improve our
market share
this focus approach has helped us
sustain superior operating and financial
metrics
we are clearly experiencing and
expecting sustained operating level
benefit of our digital model with a
stable payback matrix
going forward as we come at the journey
of rolling out our super app in phases
starting this quarter
we are creating intuitive grids
to offer more products and significantly
improve the dimension of time and
monetary value of our clients
i am happy to share with you that the
board has in aggregate approved the
distribution of over 37 percent of
quarters consolidated post tax profit as
a combination of incream and primal
dividends to shareholders
the fourth interim dividend announced
early april was distributed earlier this
week
vice record date for the final dividend
has already been communicated to
shareholders
via our stock exchange notification
i now request narayan to brief you on
operational aspects of them
thank you dinesh thank you all for
joining us today i will now walk you
through the operational performance and
recent development
our industry continues to report
healthy growth despite some micro
deterrence due to ongoing political
tensions inflationary pressures etc
this character only goes to demonstrate
the resiliency of our industry i'm
delighted to mention that we have
reported our best ever performance
during the quarter
we have reported our highest gross
client acquisition of nearly 1.5 million
total client base of over 9.2 million
10.3 percent market share in demand
accounts
nfc active client base of nearly 3.7
million
10.1 percent share
market share in msc active clients
average daily turnover of 8.6 trillion
and nearly 211 million orders
in entire fyi 2022 we added 5.3 million
clients which is
2.2 times more than fbi 2021 and 1.3
times more than what angel added over
the last 24 years
as we keep adding more clients from all
geographies our presence remains
strong covering 98 clean codes and more
importantly with client concentration of
less than 0.5 in any given 10 code
we strongly believe there are tremendous
opportunities in each of these pockets
and we will play significant role in
nurturing them
our client centric approach continues to
dominate our product offering that
provides superior their needs thus
improving the overall experience
a reflection of this is also visible
from the fact that our lifetime app
downloads were higher by 19
sequentially to nearly 22 million and
our ranking in incremental active
clients on nse during the last couple of
months improved to second
outspotting some aggressive all-around
competition
on the tech front we continue with our
organization efforts applying surgical
fixes setting up monitoring alerting for
key engineering services
this gives us ability to monitor
behavior and respond to incidents before
the incidents impact our clients we have
improved our overall escalator 99.8
percent
and with further improvements through
the year
we will be hitting four nines 99.99
within the coming year
we have embarked also on a journey to
unbox a lot of
systems
for example the back office system which
essentially handles post trade flows
through this our clients will have
access to a vast amount of data in real
time basis
first impression of this will be
available in the initial version of the
super app
our data science engines feed off of
this data to curate insights for clients
ranging from advisory to instrument
recommendations to punches
we are in the penultimate phase of our
new mobile app the forerunner to our
much awaited super app
this app is now
code complete and in advanced data and
validation phase
we will be soon ready to deliver the
first look in this quarter
this app will see multiple layers being
laid in a very planned and systematic
manner for different product offerings
to complete the journey of the super app
during the quarter there were three
major releases that were made public to
a closed group of users
to download the super app
explore trade and also provide feedback
the last two links which was done in
march significantly exceeds the features
on our current mobile application
this version will not only incorporate
personalized financial journeys for a
whole spectrum of our persona but will
also refurbish our
backend services to support it
the lease candidate
will be available across all three
platforms android
ios and web
since this is a completely new
experience for the index for
indian fintech consumer we will be
deliberate about the dial-up experience
of
all the clients
we have a migration plan in place to
ensure our clients get seamless congress
experience during the impending
transition
as an expansion of our tech capacity and
intra we are building a new
state-of-the-art data center and global
disaster recovery capabilities we
continue to build the tech team on
principles of engineering excellence
speed collaboration entrepreneurship
and
obsession with customer metrics
we further expanded our talent for this
quarter with like sapphire with hires
from top tech companies
across the world like amazon uber and
walmart labs
on the product side our focus has been
on streamlining our developments
and making changes to meet future
compliance mobs
we have undertaken some very key
improvements to our kyc journey like
allowing clients to choose between
monthly and quarterly settlement of
funds providing them as an option to add
a nominee during their kyc journey
smoothing
the process flow to enable
seamless reactivation journals
on the trade execution front our product
team improved the process and enhanced
ui for delivery trades which
led to 50 reduction in order rejection
for that segment
we dynamically also worked on placement
of various product panels which led to
high visibility
we integrated new live market trigger to
our smart api thus providing greater
stability and performance in our app
as a part of our focused effort to
provide our clients with wholesome suite
of products we have successfully
included the much sought after direct
mutual fund product
on the distribution business
this went live last weekend on our
ancient d app
over the last few quarters we continue
to emphasize on building a holistic
ecosystem to empower our clients to
invest via this channel this will
effectively lead to expanding the
lifetime relationship with our clients
we continue to witness a jump in our net
promoter score
by 80 percent in q4 f5 2022 over q3 fbi
there is a this was a result of vital
tech and product improvements carried
out in various parts of our product
onboarding some of the best tech and
digital talent over the last few
quarters has helped us achieve this
enhancements and breakthroughs this is a
precursor to our overall plan to attain
market leadership over time
human capital has always been at the
core of our strategic plans
these are the assets to create and
deliver superior experience to our
clients thus making our business robust
resilience and competitive as a part of
our efforts to keep them primed
motivated and aligned
are unaligning our combination structure
with best global practices we have
increased the portion
of restricted stock units under the lti
client 2021
maintaining the overall annual limits as
per the approvals received for the plan
we need to be explaining the details
during its opening remarks
this upfront disclosure is in line with
our efforts to follow best practices and
transparency with all our stakeholders
with this i now request winnie the world
or cfo to greet you on the financial
performance of the company
thank you over to ubini
thank you narayan good morning everyone
i will take you through the financial
snapshot for the quarterback
as mentioned by the ishmael narayan
earlier angel continued to deliver a
remarkable performance on all operating
parameters for yet another quarter which
also translated into strong financial
results
coming straight to the financial
performance quarter 4 of financial year
2022 has been our historic best
our gross revenues increased by nearly
quarter quarter to 36.9 billion
key drivers of the growth of gross
revenues were
the gross broken revenue grew by
approximately 15 quarter on quarter to
rupees 4.8 billion this accounted for
approximately 69
of our gross revenues
interest income which includes interest
on our client farming book
and interest earned from deposits with
exchanges grew by approximately 8
quarter on quarter to rupees 1 billion
this accounted for 16 of our gross
revenues
the ancillary transaction income which
is linked to the turnover of our clients
accounted for 8 of our total total gross
revenues registering a healthy growth of
63 percent quarter on quarter to rupees
581 million
depository income which contributed 4 to
the total gross income
registered a decline of nine percent
quarter on quarter this was due to muted
activity in the cash delivery segment
income from distribution of third party
products which accounted for one percent
of our gross revenues also declined by
31 sequentially due to fewer ipos
our gross broking revenues further split
as follows
share of
fno segment increased to 78 during
quarter 4 of financial year 2022.
while contribution of cash segment came
down marginally to 18
share of commodity and currency segments
remained flat at 4 and 1 respectively
the average revenue per client for the
quarter was rupees 513
this was primarily due to a higher share
of new to market clients
which were at about 85 percent of our
gross acquisitions for the quarter
basis as experience these clients
initially are low revenue attractive
but stabilize in prime inactivity with
time
this is a secular trend and is not
something to worry about
as we expand our base and market share
keeping our margins in line
our net broking revenue from less than
two-year-old clients on our platform
continued to remain robust at 76
in quarter four of financial year 2022.
this is driven by the multifold increase
in our client base over the last two
years the networking revenue on the flat
fee plan continued to witness very
strong momentum contributing a
significant 85 percent of our overall
networking revenue
share of total net income from our flat
fee clients to the consolidated total
net income grew nearly twofold to 83 in
quarter four of financial year 2022 from
in q4 of financial year 2020.
our consistent efforts to refine our
acquisition engines contributed to
higher plant addition whilst maintaining
the payback metric of our cost of
acquisition within two quarters intact
this these efforts translated to a very
healthy 55
operating margin for the quarter
keeping the pedal on the accelerator
we will continue our plans to increase
our spending
on acquiring more clients across all
geographies focusing on thinking cohorts
as prescribed by our various data points
helping up our brand awareness
building the momentum for our new app
building the best talent food
for
scaling new levels of growth which will
also include globally competitive
competitive compensation packages both
in cash and non-cash
narayan earlier explained the rationale
behind our esop mix the higher
proportion of restricted stock options
being offered to a larger and crucial
set of employees will further create a
very strong sense of ownership and as we
often call their skin in the game
as per our estimates this will lead to
an incremental annual cost of
approximately rupees 600 million for
each of the four years of wasting
of the rsus
while this will lead to an increase in
the employee costs however it should
result in a more than commensurate
growth in all our business matrix over
time under the extent accounting
standards such debits to the p l on
account of grant of stock options being
non-cash
do not impact the net worth
or our ability to distribute dividends
attractive stock options continue to be
an important vehicle of long-term
investments in the business to retain
quality talent and build a sustainable
growing and competitive organization
coupled with this
there will also be some regular salary
increases in our employee cost for the
next year
our consolidated profit after tax from
continuing operations in quarter 4 of
financial year 2022 grew by
more than 24 percent quarter on quarter
to rupees over rupees 2.2 million
once again our highest ever for any
quarter to date
consolidated earnings per share grew to
a robust rupees 24.7
per equity share on quarterly basis
coming to the fuller performance
which is also our historic best our
consolidated gross revenues grew by
seventy seven point five percent year
one year to rs 23 billion
are consolidated earnings before
depreciation amortization and tax grew
by 99 percent year on year to rupees 8.6
billion
this translates into a into about 51
margin which is at the upper end of our
guided range
our consolidated profit after tax from
continuing operations grew by nearly 110
year-on-year
to about rupees 6.3 billion
our resultant annual earnings per share
was rupees 75.8
during the year we have recommended and
paid over rupees 2.2 billion towards
dividends spread over four quarterly
entries and the final
on the balance sheet side the cash and
cash equivalent increase to
approximately 49 billion largely due to
increase in client funds
the period ending client funding book
was about 17 billion whereas borrowings
stood at about 13 billion
enhancements in tech capabilities led to
a marginal increase in fixed assets to
1.6 billion as of march 22 from 1.2
billion as of march 21
our net worth increased to approximately
16 billion as of march 2022
robust profitability along with
efficient capital utilization led to a
significant improvement in average
return on equity to 46
with this i conclude the presentation
and open the flow for further discussion
thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
too
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
the first question is from the nine of
ancient mandates from ica securities
please go ahead
yeah hi uh good morning uh
and thanks for the
opportunity my question was regarding
the nature of uh some of the growth that
we have seen in terms of clients as well
as orders so if you could give a breakup
of in the you know what percentage of
contracts in options
normally are in long was a short to give
an idea that how much of people may be
in the money and out of the money
because uh that could decide uh
kind of their persistency in terms of
their trading behavior so that is
question number one
and the question number two is that uh
based on our algo or recommendations
that we gave you know we have had a
certain kind of outperformance you know
as we have mentioned in the past so what
percentage of trades are done based on
those algorithm recommendations and
what percentage are without that so
these are the two questions thank you
yeah thank you very much uh narendra
would like to take this
uh dinner you can start i can take it
afterwards right yeah
like in retail uh nature of this
business it says that
people who come to buy options uh or
trading i would say future an option
they tend to have a lower ticket size
and they are very risk covered they are
not concerned very risk taker they are
not very knowledgeable people do write
options so mostly natural businesses
that they will buy options and mostly to
be
somewhere near the strike tides
and 10 year of like duration of this
holdings option is not more than a day
or two
so that is how actually this whole
retail market functions
uh not only if you want to add on this
yeah
and all that
yeah so just to add to what denise said
no uh i'm sure basically see if you look
at our platform we have covered
sophisticated techniques to help people
figure out figure out what option study
is to select you know and as you know
the there is a wide range of options
available here ranging from better
strike selection faster entry exits you
know better uh
better position sizing better orders and
other breeds right so all these option
underwriting strategies we have kind of
simplified them and represented them in
our insta trade product
so
using that product we let customers
essentially game out their risk and uh
figure out what is the best option
strategy to pursue for their risk
appetite at that point in time now
beyond this uh you know whether uh how
many options are in the money and out of
the money those kind of details we don't
really provide because that's uh
that's kind of not very relevant to uh
to the product offering that we offer
you know but our whole business is to
give platform capabilities to help
customers
click the best strategy to maximize
their leverage based on their risk
capital
understood
understood so so basically uh because of
the
so you are saying that there are
litigation and
close to trade
strategies that are being done to kind
of uh make them more uh
educated uh in that in their efforts
that is got it
yeah i'll get back in with you thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
karthik sani from miraida asset
management please go ahead
hi sir first of all
quotas on the uh q4 uh
numbers so my question would be around
your uh
expansion of the uh talent pool you said
that you have hired uh employees from
amazon and
ola but when i check your uh ppt the
employee base has actually uh gone down
so if you can just
help me uh with that
yeah a great question so see what we
have our strategy as we have
communicated in the past is in
continuing to scale our digital
workforce
and as we scale our digital workforce
what's happened is that we have changed
the composition the mix of people that
we are bringing in the company see angel
is
at its core we are a fundamentally
engineering driven shop okay so our
entire business when you look at our
when you look at the products we offer
when you look at the
the kind of offerings we bring to the
market the kind of future that we are
taking all of those are driven by the
product and engineering dna now this
engineering is taking place in various
aspects of our business where it's
taking place in technology in finance
it's taking place in sales and marketing
and it's taking place in in revenue and
many many other functions along with
code engineering and product so what
you're seeing here is that
the shape of the pi is changing you know
so we are hiding more for example in
duty stream and that's where jp is our
cto he's also on the call and we are
growing there by bringing top talent to
help us automate and build newer eight
systems which will allow us to scale
uh jc do you want to add a few things
here to uh give them an idea of what
kind of talent we are looking at
yeah um hello um hello
so we are basically looking at people
right who cares who are force
multipliers right um so in our industry
there are what we call 10x engineers
right
basically the few engineers who can
produce the 10x of the output of other
normal engineers so we actively look at
and go after such engineers right so
that is why we we have got them from
places like amazon and uber um
and this uh
and this so you know we can get much
more
with a very um
very skillful workforce
so then
[Music]
market share in the active uh nfc uh
client has been going up so
can i uh
assume that these are new to uh
market uh
uh customers that uh have been uh
uh targeted
or i mean if you can just uh
um yeah tell me this also
yeah so as uh you know the teenage boy
has addressed this question many times
so i would also just uh i'll just add on
to this this has been addressed in our
earnings call also see what's happening
is that we are attracting a lot of new
people to the market you know that is
testament to the product we are building
and the fact that our we are penetrating
through our marketing strategies and
areas which historically have been
underpenetrated so as more and more
newer people come to the market what's
happening is that because they are new
they are there is a gestation period you
know where it takes some time to get to
know the system learn and such so the
overall uh if you look at the uh the
average revenue yes it's uh it's kind of
stabilizing i wouldn't say it's
declining it's stabilizing to the point
where we believe that with further
improvements to come there is a
extension in the lifetime value of our
clients because these clients we are
acquiring now they are hardly 25 to 29
years old so there is a much longer time
horizon over which we can train and
cultivate this cohort base
so that's how we look at our uh our
overall business related to both active
clients as well as
our uh the net revenue realized you know
we got it and with this uh uh super app
i just wanted to ask that your other two
apps will these be
integrated
yes that is correct we will be
integrating all the experiences and
eventually retiring the other two
applications yes
okay thank you so much for all the best
thank you
next questions from the line of trade
strength
peace corps
yeah uh congratulations for a great set
of numbers a few questions from my side
uh firstly uh the next way you know we
spoke we spoke about penetration levels
in
a country
has been low
but if i look at the last six months
data
the incremental
uh
accounts that are being open every month
has been declining
incremental msc access clients that are
getting added is declining
so is there anything to read out there
to are we entering a phase where we
possibly take a breather and then
possibly the next round of grouping
might come through
uh so first the first thought will be
there our first question will be that uh
secondly
uh
uh with regards to the launch of super
app and a kind of cost associated
related to it we've seen the cost of
income ratio really come off in this uh
this quarter right around
45 percent god level uh do you think
that is a sustainable level and it
covers with the kind of you know uh
marketing that would be needed towards
super app or investments in terms of
technology and we'll also mention the
each of course that will come in so what
kind of cost income ratio we should
uh think about uh
and my last question will be
on the if i look at your you know
revenue for order both in the fndo and
the cash segment that has been declining
and i understand it will be because of
the mix between the associated persons
business and the
privacy model
but do you see this kind of stabilizing
now and no further reduction
possible that would be my three
questions thanks
okay so you've asked three questions so
let me collate the answers and uh one by
one we will address them okay so i'll
also loop in uh dinesh wise
so okay let's first take the meta
question that you asked right about what
dinesh talked about in his opening
opening uh
opening monologue right see
we all know that the market is seriously
underpenetrating i think that's that's a
very well understood fact it's barely at
four to five percent and so clearly as
more and more and more customers come to
the market there is
obviously going to be a learning curve
for the whole industry not not just for
any broker it's part of the whole
industry is going through the collective
learning course now in this collective
learning phase the type of products the
type of journeys that these customers
want that is what angel is paying
attention to see we are not so
particularly razor focused on getting
the on screening the last rupee out of
the out of the out of the client
as much as we are interested in
understanding what is the journey that
they care about because it is ultimately
that journey which will lead to greater
rewards and greater investment behavior
so if you look at our strategy it has
never been around uh you know around uh
it has never been
uh a you know the better way to put it
it's never been focused around just a
rupee optimization equivalent it's
mostly focused on build the right
journey understand what is it that this
new cohort base wants you know cares
about what kind of investment patterns
make sense for them and then build the
right experience on top so obviously in
that in that evolution which we have
started over the last
two three years you will see that
our
of our net orders is actually going up
you know and it's going up across all
the cohort basis you know
now if you go one step further and look
at what kind of better experiences we
want to produce even our
new features such as insta trade or
option simplified they are resonating
with this new age customer because this
new each customer wants that inherent
simplicity in the product
so our
strategy is going to be around
discovering those experiences and
building those experiences based on
machine learning and ai and that is one
of the biggest differentiators for angel
from everybody else in the competition
this is one thing they are doing much
better and very differently
now uh your second question uh so sorry
it was three questions so i'll try to go
step by step so your second one is about
the cost to income ratio i will have
viniq take this but just to give you
just a broader business sense on it
ultimately
once the super app gets live there is
going to be an investment in uh in
call to action you know and getting more
people to uh
than most people
to kind
of um you know onboard their journeys
their existing german boundaries so
clearly there is a there is a cost but
all of this is factored into our uh met
operating plan so i will have vinnie
just uh give a sense on uh
on the uh on the income numbers so
really can you cover that
sure that is here yeah
so um
uh fish what happens is that we've uh
historically as you see we've been
improving our cost to income ratio over
the last few quarters ever since we went
digital and that trend is going to
continue now uh in some quarters there
might be some higher cost
for some uh
you know like as i said about
salaries that we have given in the first
uh form april
so those things will be there but over
by and large i think there will be the
cost to income ratio will be improving
uh as we go along in our digital journey
and definitely with the launch of the
super app this is going to improve
you mentioned is 60 crores per annum for
the next four years
that's right so uh the
stock our issues that we have
granted yesterday
for those rsu's and the ones which we
expect to grant in the next few months
for those uh the investing period is
four years and the cost is amortized
over the four year period so this is
going to be the annual cost
approximately but then if i understand
this correctly generally this is on a
declining way wherein in the first is
the first year we have the bulk of the
cost then it reduces to the technology
based on building up working period so
and you're saying that it could be a 60
crore for anon so is it a 240 crore to
be amortized
over four years and it would be the
maintained and reducing going ahead or
it will be 60 per annum
this is based on the black scrolls model
uh so every year we redo the model based
on assumptions and uh tentatively i've
given you a 60 common cost that is going
to be there
and what
as i had mentioned in the call in the
earlier part of the call if this is a
non-cash
debit to
and there is no search related use of
course in uh fi 22.
this this will be new completely new
yeah this covers mostly all the use of
cost that is there
so 22 we had nothing
okay
yeah so uh we don't actually uh you know
we don't give macro level data like that
we just compute the revenue in the
segment and the number of orders that
you give
uh that number has been on a decline
and i understand it would be because of
the mix between the ap business and the
black free model uh but do you think
this will get normalized over the next
uh
and we will not see any further declines
or how do you see this see that
happening
yeah so see the first of all the
obviously the ratio is just a simple uh
division is always misleading right
because it's looking at a very aggregate
picture now i think uh the
the question that we are asked that that
we uh that we are asking ourselves is
what is the user behavior behind
uh you know behind the uh
what are the trends behind the numbers
which are leading to this transformation
right now i do see the numbers
stabilizing there is no precedent for it
to uh
you know for it to go any other way
except to stabilize over a period of
time but it's hard to tell whether it
will take another two quarters or three
quarters or a few years but what we do
know is that as the overall
uh traction on our products improve
right the net gains will come largely
based on new journeys that we built
around fno around options trading and
also other uh
segments so we are looking at the next
picture because that is a better
indicator of what the market uh where
the or where the customers wants are
heading you know so that is a much
bigger uh
question for us to answer rather than
looking at a multi-level trend that
might be useful but it's only useful
in its own uh bubble if you will you
know okay
okay all right thank you i'll come back
thank you
participants who wishes to ask a
question may press star and one
participants are even requested to
please limit their questions to two per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line
of akshay ashok from prabhudar
please go ahead
yeah hi congratulations on a very good
setup numbers i just had a few questions
what are the steps you are taking to
increase the client activation rate and
what is the activation rate now because
i think the activation rate before was
around 38 39
because now that you have added so many
clients the next step would be to
activate them right because if markets
start falling or there's a downturn
the best way to continue maintaining
your gross broking revenues and
everything would be
uh having a higher current activation
rate so what are the steps you guys are
taking in that direction
yeah so we have our chiefs uh you know
we have devendra kumar which runs
revenue on the line so i'll hand it over
to him but let me just
add a few sentences first so actually
our activation numbers have been uh i've
been studying strong as you guys as you
guys know over the last uh almost 24
months now especially this last year we
have seen a significant increase right
now what we what we believe is that
through a combination of better
reference schemes through a combination
of
better
first trade and uh you know the first
the the first on-boarding journey we
believe there is potential to actually
apply data science and ml and take this
activation to the next level
so i'll have davinder talk about some of
the key initiatives there what is the
client activation rate now it goes 37 38
right
divider you want to take over
yeah hi everyone
all right
yeah
so we don't disclose our activation
ratio but you can take a number of
tennessee active clients upon the base
which will be you know coming over the
new client edition is around 40 42
percent but uh we don't disclose this
number uh on the answer that what are
the steps that we're taking to increase
the actual activation ratio i think uh
marine tells the court rightly that we
have taken very data science oriented
approach we are which where we are
creating different cohorts of clients uh
based on the kind of profile that
they're coming with and customizing the
journey
that the take in terms of getting you
know the first investment download
where we have projects like no on
boarding kit where the first time
trading first time investment the first
entry experience of the client is taken
care of the first time you know uh
investment instruments and so and so
forth so what we are doing is you know
basically looking at a mix of these two
things uh particularly where a
forward-based approach and you know
building new uh kind of instruments or
not other instruments journeys for the
clients and exposing the right products
for the first timers
through which we are planning to go
ahead okay nowadays the first timers
when they join your app when how long
does it take for them to do a trade
so it
so
i think we don't disclose the
information but
said this in the past right within about
six months we kind of break it you know
the
mostly about more than half our clients
are active within the first year now
obviously within that we don't uh you
know
because of competitive reasons we don't
divulge any more info than that but okay
based on that you know we can put a good
approximation on how effective our
strategies are
yeah finals are this commodity market
share games are continuing to be very
strong what is the reason for that and
this cash market share why again this
quarter slightly it has dipped
because the peak margin norms i think
are being implemented right when why is
commodity market share gaining so
quickly
commodity is clearly clearly a testament
to our substantial you know we are truly
the market leader there based on our
super excellent research and our
excellent product i mean if you yourself
haven't used the product i would
strongly encourage you actually to try
it out because you'll see it firsthand
you know
the product is beautifully done that's
one of the main reasons we are and also
combined with our super excellent uh
research team uh led by omar singh and
the company you know they have done a
phenomenal job at uh exceeding our
position there and uh regarding that the
other question you know see
those those changes you know will happen
as the regulations keep changing so
those are uh ultimately uh that playing
field is going to get leveled we're fine
and uh we don't see much advantage in
those other
those other things
so uh you know to answer uh this
question on the commodity market share
which is growing
uh so if you look at you know the
exchange
volume you know
somewhere the future volumes are
stagnated at uh 20 25 000
uh
recently the large growth is coming in
the option market
and we were kind of you know very early
uh adopter and you know provider of
options on the mobile platform to our
customers you know that's one of the
major reason that you know we see as a
you know market share growing
uh second important factor you know is
that all our customers has a you know
fungible limit so when they
have a margins with us you know across
the segments they can trade they don't
have to actually earmark their phones
you know towards the segments but in
industry you know that that is not
available so not so these are the two
large factors which are uh driving the
market shares uh higher uh so you know
the uh the optional volume you know uh
while future is at 20 25 000 crores uh
option volume is has grown to a level of
roughly around 15 000 crores a day and
that's where our market share is uh you
know very high and at a blended level
that's how you know we are reporting uh
40 plus market share
oh okay okay thank you thank you that's
it from us
thank you
the next question is from the lioness
athlete from high tongue securities
please go ahead
yeah thank you for giving me the
opportunity so just on your instagram
platform i wanted to understand the
number of users that we have what is the
user base of this
sorry your uh yeah so
insta trade see we don't give a future
by future uh you know uh breakdown of
our monthly active or daily active users
but it's it's uh it's a pretty
substantial portion a good portion of
our uh of our active clients that's all
that's all we can say
okay sure so just another question on uh
stock options so if my understanding is
correct currently if if the person you
know on settlement date if the long is
in the money he has to take delivery
compulsively is that understanding
correct
uh
so uh
darwin can you answer this
good morning
basically
in an option if there is an in the money
option that the customer is holding
in case if the margins are sufficient
from the customer we allow the customer
to keep the balances
but if the margins are there there is a
margin called done to the customers and
accordingly
there are actions have been taken
okay
okay so thank you that's it
thank you
the next question is from the lioness
nilay sritani from boix from mutual fund
please go ahead
uh hi sir thanks for the opportunity and
congratulations on the day set of number
my first question was of course on the
active clients when i see today our
active total client number is anywhere
in the range of 40 percent but when i
compared it to someone like zeruda it is
not worth 60 percent so i wanted to
understand what is why the divergence
won and second what are we doing to
drive this active because this is the
number of trades which will write the
top-line growth for us so want to
understand what are we doing on these
parameters
so see first of all you know
we uh we can't comment on our
competitor's acceleration ratio because
those data is that data is highly
subjective you know this is as good as
mine now uh but the bigger question
really is that
our activation numbers as i said is uh
is almost half you know it's almost 50
percent and uh of course we don't get
into too many details of how we split
and everything but the the key thing
here is that many times our competitors
when they are they run incentive schemes
where which uh you know which uh which
are of the types of you know giving
somebody a free ptf while opening up
opening an account and things like that
so when you do when you take uh you know
uh exclusive customer acquisition
strategies such as giving out free ads
then by definition if i open an account
to redeem it i have to activate so that
is never a good indication of uh whether
the
the activation is inherent activation or
it is just a forced function of open
revenue realization which uh the you
know which the client wants to get right
so what we however what we have seen is
that
in our case the activation numbers we
are reporting they are consistently
going up and they've consistently gone
up uh it was in the just in the low 30s
as as uh as early as about two years ago
and now as i told you the numbers are
significantly higher right so i see this
numbers going further up as we continue
to improve our data science and machine
learning based journals
and this is what davinder was hinting in
his uh uh was was
talking about a few minutes ago where he
talked about you know our approach in
improving the
first
signing to trade experience
uh
introducing better
cohort selection and infusing and
introducing better targeting for our
clients to help them
board and start their journeys i think
between these three steps
we have uh we have a very clear and
winning strategy for driving the number
over a period of time
you got it and in the new app the super
app that is helping us to drive the
activation rate management for the
broken uh business
yeah so the data is uh you know because
the super app has been in uh
it's been uh you know it's been in the
works and now now we are getting
obviously a lot of earlier uh early
feedback
yes the trend is going in that direction
but i need one more quarter's worth of
data before i can affirmatively answer
that question you know but right now
it's looking like it's it's obviously
the trending up because we have run
numerous studies but as we launch it
further and scale further i'll have a
more measured answer for you right but
right now the of the answer based on
what we have seen so far yes
got it
those are my questions and thank you so
much for replying to each other thank
you so much thank you thank you
thank you
the next question is from the lineup is
from invesco please go ahead
thanks uh so i have a couple of
questions
so first is uh so i remember narayan
joining the company one year back
uh the first work anniversary uh this i
think this month itself
um so
so i remember that
you're because you were quite keen on
the super app investment
and your work when's good to see that
you're seeing uh it's coming to
uh it's becoming live in beta mode
um so i just wanted to understand the so
obviously this year was an investment
year for your super app
and how should we look about the
investments in next year in this and
earlier in one of the earlier question
you spoke about
the costs uh the incremental cost that
you will incur to get clients on super
app
but but but just thinking about it it's
just a migration of the existing
clients from your existing app to super
app and it's a normal uh client
acquisition cost that you any which ways
have every year so i'm just wondering
how is this
cost different uh to acquire customer on
super app that's question number one and
second is obviously uh how should we
think about investments next year and uh
even the sustainable margins uh that
that you have in mind and then i and
then i have a second question after that
thank you thank you for uh asking the
question so see first of all you know as
as you know right once the
super app as uh as the super app gets
baked and more and more people
transition to the super app there is
always going to be a long tail of
customers who are going to who are going
to take some time to migrate over
now this journey
uh this migration that we are going to
be that we are talking about here is
going to be
one of the largest migrations in india
and in fact one of the largest in the
globe because we are talking about a
wholesale move of more than 9 million
clients to the new app right so clearly
there is a there will be a cost
associated with it now we have actually
factored in all those costs and built
the right kind of tooling and
infrastructure far ahead of time to uh
ready ourselves for this uh
upcoming switch and this switch is going
to be collectively excellent for our
business and great for our clients great
for our clients because they get a
better journey and better experience so
from a cost perspective from an
engineering and product perspective
there is no much uh delta as you rightly
indicated because that cost was already
baked in uh and it was baked in from the
day i joined the company right that's
what we've been doing for last week for
the last four quarters
now but there is another cost the cost
is see if you look at our
our strategy you know we have not really
played big in our brand space you know
we are uh we have kept our we have kept
our heads hunkered down and just
exclusively focused on building the
right product but now that we have built
this
this kick-ass product we want to know
get it to the masses which means we need
to start investing more in increasing
our brand visibility throughout our
industry you know throughout our uh you
know with our clients and this is
something that this year is going to be
a big investment for us big in the sense
it's going to be
more than what we have done in the past
right we want to get out there we want
to tell the message get more clients
onto the system
then uh
so that's one of the key bets this year
and then subsequent years you know
we
firmly believe that
our
uh the next wave of growth
will come from risk and ops
but the person that you know the team
that
figures out a scalable way to unlock the
value in automating these systems can
innovate much much faster for the
customer
so i look at the next two years as a
start of that journey when we are going
to take a look at our existing risk
systems our existing processes our
existing back office systems and our
existing customer experience journeys
and automate and bring that to the next
level and that is where the next few
years of uh off spend will go and that's
largely driven by engineering and
product you know
so hopefully that gives you a sense of
what's coming immediately and then
what's coming in uh let's say a year
from now
yeah yeah i understand just follow up on
that um see one of your inspiration is
to become the largest uh
broker of the country
and today the largest broker has not
relied on marketing he has relied on his
product word of mouth
but but you seem to be taking a
different journey so
why why not let your product speak for
itself and why spend marketing dollars
that's a fantastic question and
the main reason for that is because now
that we have this is the first time if
you look at our apps right we have had
two different apps we have that angel b
we have ad bar and then we have had some
prior versions so
clearly there is no impetus for building
that organic traffic organic traffic
builds once you have a consistent a
consistent platform for sharing your
message
so
the reason we have not had that
opportunity is because we have just not
had that product so far
but that is going to change with the
super app so as you as i play the movie
out over the next year two years clearly
there will be more uh
more emphasis on organic but at the same
time our market itself our job is to
also expand the market
and if we can spend more and get more
customers on the platform while keeping
our four business metrics at a
profitable level then to me it makes
more business sense to go spend that
money you know there's no point in
keeping that and
and trying to super optimize at this
stage because at this stage it's all
about capturing the market
so it's a two-fold it's a two-pronged
answer the reason we are not invested
much in organic is which i just answered
earlier because it's been a platter of
apps and that is changing with our super
apps
and once we have the super app clearly
the emphasis on organic is baked right
into the app itself and then the second
question is even if we have that i still
believe that we need to continue to
spend and expand this market and bring
more and more clients into the system as
long as we can maintain the healthy
level of operational uh you know
operational profits and excellence
sure i get that
now the second part of the question so
while we've discussed the costs now
let's uh
talk about the revenue potential revenue
from here while while i understand then
i appreciate that your larger objective
is to improve the activation rate in
your core business have give a better
experience and thereby increase your
broking revenues further
but in terms of diversifying into other
sources of revenue while you've already
integrated
direct mutual funds but obviously it's
direct so it is more of added experience
to clients and revenue accretion
your second
intention of getting into mutual funds
it's some time away but again it has it
will be passive focus so again less
revenue uh creative uh how about other
products in terms of
do you intend to add
loan again securities while you've
spoken in the past about lending
products
and that is something this cohort the
young cohort would be quite keen to
explore and not so much
of the savings products given there
given their age profile
so so while
while you have your beta product ready
but how do you think about the
diversified or different revenue sources
and what is the time frame that you have
in your mind
see uh you know
i firmly believe that
there is a lot of money left on the
table as far as broking itself is
concerned you know so
i i am a firm believer that we need to
stay razor focused on winning broken and
that is the only thing that matters to
me for the next year
and i want to be very very specific
about it right because
when what we have seen is when customers
when our
and you have seen this with our company
does also
it's very easy for us to launch 10
different things and do a poor job with
all of them
what we need to do is think about how we
can get and unlock revenue opportunities
in our space itself because ultimately
the next disruption is going to come
from here only now obviously that
includes things like considering
products like loan again securities and
such and clearly we are running those
experiments on our side as well and when
the time comes you'll be seeing us
launch those products and launch those
capabilities
now in terms of
direct mutual funds and other auxiliary
products see the
the the reason we launched direct mutual
funds is because
it is our customers who are actually
looking elsewhere because they have an
unmet need
so
we are actually you know it's it's
almost like our latent client base which
is forced to look outside our product
because we currently don't have anything
so that made a lot more business sense
because we want to give them a wealth
garden and this is something revenue uh
the members team is currently
strategizing on and you know as we look
at building out this wealth garden we
look at customers today which we are
acquiring and they are hardly 28 29
years old so our lifetime value is
you're looking at a 20 30 year lifetime
value so we don't want to we don't want
to uh you know uh we don't want these
customers to self cannibalize and kind
of go elsewhere when we can give them a
much superior integrated product in our
own platform so this is the main reason
why we are why we did the direct mutual
fund launch you know it's not because
it's the it's the thick of the movement
or whatever right we don't we don't do
uh uh you know we don't approach new
businesses that way now there are other
opportunities also like lending is
another one insurance is another one but
even before we get there i believe that
there is opportunities to look at fixed
deposits there's opportunity to look at
aggregate aggregate fixed deposit
products there is opportunities to
expand our and more revenue
opportunities and commodities there is
obviously opportunities for the route in
uh insurance products which we are also
selling on our platform i believe there
are as a platform company there will be
opportunities to unlock those
capabilities in the you know once the
super app platform is uh is ready and
it's sold out
so that's how i'm thinking about the
next year two years in three years
ah sure sure that makes sense i wish you
all the best thank you
thank you
the next question is from the lion of
ankit babin from shipkam ventures please
go ahead
yeah good afternoon
so my first question is
now without this super app you are
growing access suppose x percentage so
now
we cannot hear you clearly
am i audible now yes please go ahead
yeah so sir uh uh now without the super
app suppose you people were going at x
percentage now with this app coming in
uh can that growth go to like 1.2 x or
1.3x if yes how and if no then why does
that
yeah
so great uh great question it's a very
fundamental question so thank you for
asking so see what has happened now is
that
the
our customers expectations from the app
and from the product have changed
so even if we sit and do nothing yes
it's true that our app is you know our
current app is also growing at a pretty
phenomenal rate right and we are
actually uh
in fact i think we mentioned in the call
that we are
you know
we are right now uh in a very seriously
strong leading position as far as new
clients are concerned uh you know for
the first uh for this past quarter
now this trend line is continuing
because obviously the journey is a big
thing and such but see what has happened
is that the behavior of the cohort is
changing customers now they're they're
expecting a better personalized journey
and this is what dinesh has said in his
opening statement is that you know this
personalized journey is what our clients
future needs are so we have to hedge
against that
and we have to build that journey
in the most effective way possible and
that is unfortunately not possible in
our current act
this is the main reason we have we
decided to build the super app because
our ambitions are far bigger than what
you see on our current uh atma
application you know so to give us space
to innovate we we embarked on the super
app strategy now what we see as to uh in
terms of your next question or how we
see the the ramp up right
i am extremely confident that once the
migration is done like you know it will
take a call it will take two to two and
a half hours to kind of get that over
with right once all the customers are
into the new platform and actually take
the new app right
i'm definitely confident that the uh
both the acquisition rate as well as the
activation increase acquisition rate
will go
now whether it goes up 2x or 3x or half
x it's uh you know it remains to be seen
because the super app also
is built with a uh with a very fast
customer closing loop in mind so we do
know that we can iterate much faster
than the competition once we have this
platform so i am very confident that
you're going to see a double-digit
growth once the
you know once this
you know once the full transition is
complete and the buck starts rolling you
know on the super app so that's how we
are approaching it as a
company and as a management team
can i have something to that yeah yeah
please probably go ahead
yeah hi uh well that's a great question
um my name is prabhakar tiwari uh i work
as a chief officer here
so as the narayan has mentioned you know
and there has been a theme throughout
that you know product will play a huge
role they're a tech and broad company
and in terms of growth it will impact
both our acquisition from them and our
revenue funds when in terms of
acquisition today we operate in a
certain channel mix some other question
was regarding you know why the
competition is kind of growing without
marketing dollars and marilyn answered
that and there's a blended approach
there is also aggregate competition
which is in another extreme so far we
have taken a blended approach of both
organic and paid in future you know that
blending will change both for organic
and graphical kind of channels and also
one important thing i want to
communicate that what you have seen last
year is our rebranding moving from angel
broken to angel one and i'm very happy
to share that you know with angel one we
have now 84 awareness just for angel one
in in two quarters
you know okay now what you will see this
year uh with the new app being stable
the migration being complete is a new
positioning and the new position is
around the power of data and technology
for everyday investors we believe both
the product experience and the entire
positioning around it will definitely
help us in the top of the funnel uh
opening up the top of the funnel for
more growth and also will kind of make
our lower front more efficient so that
the next wave of growth as narayan spoke
about would come at a much much
lower cost or in a more cost efficient
manner
thank you
okay so my second question is now what i
understand um from your business is that
you people have a very high operating
leverage model
so uh you know if you continue to grow
at a very high growth rate definitely
there would be an operating leverage and
i understand that that operating
leverage would be utilized or would take
care of your increased investments in
say a client acquisition or the
increased employee cost and everything
so
just for my understanding is it fair to
assume that what you have done in fi 22
in terms of top line growth and bottom
line growth can be replicated
say for the next two years also
in spite of the increased investments in
in these areas
yeah yes so what you're seeing is that
uh you know the
the parameters of the business are not
going to change you know we are
fundamentally operating within the same
envelope
just the assumptions and just the growth
rates and just uh our investments have
changed within them but the overall
metric and the overall framework stays
the same so your answer so yes i do see
that over the next year two years three
years i foresee the same kind of
traction you know
yeah okay that's helpful answered last
one short question what is your client
acquisition target for refer 23 and you
added some 5.3 million
last year can you double it up
in in the coming year
yes see we don't divulge that but yes i
mean we are looking to uh we can say
that yeah we'll be for helping for a
company like at our stage which is
growing the rate at which we are growing
yeah i mean doubling that is a very
aggressive and very global topic
okay and any targets for client
acquisition sorry client active client
ratio i mean from current 42 say 45 50
where do you see
yeah any anything that is uh that you
know we want obviously anything north of
uh 55 56 is a good number to get you
know so and we are very close to those
numbers already so uh obviously there is
no upper limit on how high it can go but
this finite math dictates how i can go
but my uh you know we don't talk about
those targets but you can assume that we
want to be within that range that we
have already discussed you know the 50
60 range between that
that's helpful sir thank you and all the
rest
thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants
request you to please limit your
questions to super participant
if you have a follow-up question you may
read or in queue
the next question is from the line of
pratik buddha from nepal india mutual
fund please go ahead
yeah he said just two questions one you
know we seem to suggest that this that
the migration to super app is a switch
rather than a phase like migration
can that be a threat in the sense like
let's say customers take some time for
adoption of new customer journeys on the
new super app
uh how do you think about that and and
you know ultimately if let's say
in a closed group the
the sample set is quite small related to
what you have as a group clients right
so if the experience is more good
and if you do it as a switch how would
you uh you know rectify or
you know how because that there could be
a loss of momentum right so how should
you think about that that's question
number one
and the second question is you know it's
been answered in some parts but last
month you'll see a lot of supplements
you seem to outperform even the market
leader when it comes to nfc access
client ads on the existing app
so how should i think about
what is writing this
and lastly uh uh
just an extension uh overall you seem to
suggest that the sweeper app will take
you into a different trajectory when it
comes to revenue
so how how do we think about this
revenue is it is it more client ads or
is it higher r2 or is it more
diversified or ancillary revenues what
takes you into the next week so three
questions right now see first of all the
the uh as with any app strategy
the minute you
the minute a company pivots and launches
a super app there is always a runway
period you know many times uh investors
uh they get education you know they they
want to wait only for one quarter before
they see results and oftentimes it
doesn't work that way because when you
hear me new experiences they take time
but they are done with a long-term
perspective in mind so
we have built the super app and the
journeys based on what the cohort
behavior we want to drive on our
platform going forward
so uh what we have you know
in terms of the switching as you then
that's a very important question right
see we have we are launching the product
in phases
and uh each there is there are gates for
scaling up and scaling down our adoption
curve based on customer feedback so we
close the loop with the customers pretty
quickly and we continue to
iterate based on feedback that we are
actually getting from the from the
clients and this innovative phase has
been going on the app has been in uh
development and we've had plenty you
know tens of thousands of beta customers
now for almost uh
almost six to eight months you know so i
will have uh christine who is our chief
product operator he's on the line okay
can you just talk a little bit about
what kind of uh you know strategies we
are pursuing to scale up the
uh the uh the norm on adoption
yeah yeah
um for and i have five perfect uh
fantastic question there so so as aaron
mentioned right over we have been
experimenting with this clg
uh data group uh
kind of cohort from last couple of
quarters
as well as new customers so we will
continue on that calibrated approach in
fact
it will be a
quite a measurable rollout we call it
stage measurable rollout
where the
the x percent of the user who will get
it will again repeat
we'll measure
their revenue their fis
fourier revenues their activation and
acquisition
acquisition across various channels
where the referral is working
right over there organic is moving up so
between these needles and these matrices
and these funnels will be calibrated
approach and we have a capability to
kind of quickly address in case there is
a rf drop and up and can and kind of uh
move this leading from five and
probably experiment
and the second question on you guys
outperforming
uh the active client i mean flying
conditions outperforming the market lead
or any thoughts how have you been able
to do this yes so yeah yeah so uh
actually i should i should uh specify
that uh you know we have been we while
our current super our current app has
been kind of in low touch mode you know
the there have been many capabilities
and features which have been introduced
towards the tailing part of last year
before we called the code free and now
you're starting to see our clients take
advantage of that
and you're seeing more uh momentum build
around those okay like obviously
instagram is one option there's a lot of
others in the pipes
so we should not downplay what is what
we have done in the past year on our
existing level and then other thing is
uh clearly our investments in digital
marketing have paid off you know we have
we are one of the first companies to
take a a very uh a very nuanced look at
applying both area and ml techniques to
our client activation strategy and that
has obviously resulted in better better
better cohort selection and better uh uh
realization of leads which are coming
through the funnel because we have also
invested heavily in optimizing that
funnel right from the time the lead
comes to the door to the time we
actually open an account so there's been
a combination of both
better product improvements better tech
capabilities better system of time and
obviously uh digital improvements in the
entire activities
yeah
so
putting this to our address right so on
improvement there so the answer to that
is a lot of our uh
strategy has been fixing the back-end
services which apply by the way to both
the platforms so anything which we do
for super app is kind of also helping
the existing platform inevitably so the
robustness of the ability of that is
also getting the benefits so you will
see uh so as a level customer continues
what drives it is it client acquisitions
or higher revenue per client or
ancillary revenues or it's a mix of all
the three
maybe just
it's a it's a mix of all the three
driven by the user journey what
ultimately drives greater revenue in
any digital business is the customer
experience and the fact that our
journeys are in line with what customers
needs and expectations are so in the
super app the entire journey is built
around a uh it's tuned very much to
what our
you know to what our clients
capabilities are their risk profiles are
and uh ultimately helping them uh you
know on board with the system in a much
more simpler way which obviously doesn't
exist in our current app you know so
it's a combination of two or three
things there
and lastly any update on amc
yeah so uh as we mentioned right we are
all we're already uh the process is
underway and uh we need to you want to
just uh share some updates the latest
update on the amc side
sure
so the people on the amc uh as you are
aware in september last year we made the
application for being principal approval
the process is on
city is doing that due diligence and
hopefully in the next
few months we should have the
in-principle approval in place
fantastic and all of the best for the
future thanks
thank you
if that answers your question mr
president
yeah all my questions answered thanks
the next question is from the lion of
kajal from isaac please go ahead
hello hi uh
congratulations on good set of numbers
so
i just wanted to once understand that we
had initially started as a
transformation journey
and now that we have seen that the
brokerage and the total revenue is 78
percent around that only but the mix has
changed significantly towards fno
versus cash so do you think
like almost 78 percent is now
fno and cash is just less than 20 so do
you think cash
going ahead is going to be very very
insignificant portion of the total
revenue
and how do you see your revenue mix
evolving
yeah
see the cache segment is uh first of all
you know i should say that it's a it's
obviously an important segment like all
the other segments that we have right
but clearly there is a uh industry trend
which is buckling the whole uh
the whole uh the whole mix as you as you
have rightly pointed out
and honestly when we look at the
business right it's very hard for uh for
us to say whether it will stabilize that
uh you know at this number or what the
overall uh mix would look like but we do
know that the the in terms of total
number of orders and the total number of
orders has gone up dramatically in this
past year as you've seen right we are
focused on driving that aggregate volume
up because that is a macro level trend
which we can control uh which is not
controlled but we can we can we can
create and device strategies to drive
back
versus uh cherry picking on which one of
these individual approaches will work
so and there's also future innovations
planned on the product side which will
which uh you'll see us uh you know which
will drive up value on both on all of
these segments actually also going
forward so it's hard to predict where
the puck will land uh but you know we
can say that uh it still uh
the mix will remain healthy and the
overall aggregate number will be the one
that we are focused on you know
and what will be the share of elbow
trading in our overall volume
so right now it's very non-significant
in the it's not even material also
because we don't have any particular
algo products if you will
we we have our
system-generated product which is called
arq
and uh that is something that uh you
know we've built in-house and uh but
that's also not that doesn't technically
qualify as a algo but you know so to
answer your question it's a very it's
it's close to zero at this point you
know the
uh
significant portion is ar2 giving you
a arq is a meaningful chunk of
people who come and onboard onto our
systems and try out yes but it's not uh
it's not uh it's still a a product in
alpha if you will you know so it's still
not fully baked into our main line
offering so it's something as we
continue to break that journey into the
super app uh we are expecting that as a
service subscription there will be more
uh action coming on that side
but at this point it's kind of uh
in a different
bucket so and the last question is on
the employee's side so you have said as
always that the mix has been changing so
increments are you seeing that pressure
on the cost side for getting those
employees because
market is good for the iit side or the
engineering
candidate so how do you see that going
up for you
so you know
we started this transformation
journey of three years back you know
and in these past three years we have
had the
uh you know we've had the advantage of
uh owning our strategy every year
so now we have hit a point we have hit
that sweet spot where our where the unit
economics of hiring and uh the whole
cost curve
it's uh it's perfectly uh settled into
our system so there is no surprises
anymore
so i don't see uh any of these costs
cost fluctuations affecting us
dramatically because we already have the
playbook on what it takes to attract top
talent in the market what kind of
structures compensations we need to put
in place and what kind of reward
structure makes most sense for our
business so we have had almost top 12
months worth of uh break time to kind of
eliminate that uncertainty you know at
this point
so there's no uncertainty on that side
from our side
thank you so thank you very much
thank you
the next question is from the lion of
shaheen smith from hdfc securities
please go ahead
good afternoon and congratulations on a
great threat uh so so most of my
questions have been answered uh just two
questions from my side uh so you know
what are the new investors doing and how
is their trading intensity uh given that
now we have people moving back to
offices
uh could we expect these kind of trains
in the derivative segment to continue
for the industry
yeah so uh see
i mean now people have been going back
to work almost six months now right i
mean everybody is uh
those those uh those dark days of
forward are behind us you know
but uh and what we've seen is that in
these two two or three quarters which
have preceded us you know especially the
last two quarters which we all agree
that they have kind of been in the post
era if you will right the while the
behavior has changed the
there has been no uh
there's been no acceptable impact on our
volumes or anything like that because as
you yourself have seen from our results
there's no uh the stability has been the
naturalization has already effect so our
business is already growing at a healthy
metric and i don't anticipate any uh
further changes
and in terms of changes in uh investment
behavior see obviously because many
clients are young and new
uh their ticket size is still the same
interestingly so they're still having
the same ticket size but obviously the
the uh the approach
with which they enter the market is very
different different right it is driven
by many social based investing teams and
things like that which uh is not true
for folks that are in their mid-thirties
or a little bit later in life so there
is a explicit change in behavior and
this is why i was telling you that we
need to we're selling the others right
we need to build this journey now
because there is a clearly a there is a
tailwind in the market that
that the expectation has changed
and that is what we need to get ahead of
you know
thank you as the participant left the
queue we'll move to the next question
which is from the line of prenup gupta
from esk investment managers please call
it
yeah hi good afternoon and
congratulations good set of numbers
uh i have two questions uh one is for
the answer um uh so
so when you talk about the supernat and
how
it can be a it will be the key driver
for you know taking the revenue
trajectory to the next level
just wanted to understand that initially
when they are migrating uh
our existing base to the
to the super app uh
typically our given that our
revenue large part of the contributors
fno which is a flat fee base
how do we
engage with customers more on how do we
see
the same set of customers do larger
amount of trades which will then
eventually drive revenue i understand
that when you acquire new customers new
trades will be added but
how do you engage more through the super
app and uh
increase the current uh current rating
volumes of the current customer base
that's the first question
so see you know
the the easiest way to uh to drive up
these numbers is by addressing customer
strain points now if you look at our
existing ad our existing app is super
excellent in many dimensions but an area
that we are not uh that we really need
to do a better job is our reporting
systems so anytime
if you
introduce a uh
if you introduce a uh
you know
a
a constraint or if you kind of dampen
that journey obviously the user is
discouraged from spending more on your
platform you know why would they come
and agree for a substantive journey and
this is what will change in the super
app because in the super app we have
taken of holistic approach like on the
main page itself on the super app you
can see your overall portfolio you can
see your asset mix you can see what's
your composition of stocks bonds you can
see your risk profile everything in one
clean neat package
then there are videos and structures
towards the end which cue cards that let
you figure out what kind of capabilities
features you want
and i'll let ankit add a few more to the
uh okay just why didn't you add a few
sentences on how the super app journeys
are pretty much like the simplicity
which we are adding which which is
bounded by our personalization
capability starting from the home page
with smaran mentioned uh even if you are
an fms
upgrade will pop up for you earlier
in your history the recommendations will
which is much more crucial right any app
has to be much more predictable so this
app is giving you a very predictable
experience uh to a fashion trader as
well as to say a new guy where we are
stuck in where to activate this guy
right
what should be my first trade
this is also a reflection of um the
entire state the experience which are uh
significantly revamping in our city at
the the transparency level which is one
of the tenets of our super baby
will be at the industry first
so uh and then and one one more point
it's also the speed of the platform
which will be which which is i think a
very key driver for an option trader
which will be significantly better
we are improving on our streaming
services uh we are improving in our
classroom for chartings so these are a
couple of initiatives which will be
invisible
right so you know uh the main the
meta point here is that generally people
the question to ask is why are people
are people spending the most
that they can on our platform
are we realizing 100 percent or 150
percent of the revenue potential from
every client and the answer to that
question is on our current platform the
answer is no we are not because the fact
and why are we not realizing that
revenue potential because in our current
app there are many journals which are
not as fully baked or as fully mature as
we want them to be
so naturally when we move to the super
app obviously the volume will go up
because the revenues have been for the
the journeys have been fully baked now
whether you i you know it's hard for me
to predict whether you're going to see
it all in just one quarter or will it
take us you know three quarters or so
till the whole uh flow becomes
normalized and i think that kind of
variance is to be expected from any tech
any tech business you know so we are
giving ourselves also that time so that
we can avoid any false start and not uh
you know not shoot ourselves in the foot
before uh we're doing any big mic you
know before doing any big migration like
this right it has to be done in a very
thoughtful way
so
yeah man can i add something
yes please not good yeah so uh just to
answer this
someday what happens is there are
different types of clients they are
first timers coming in they are traders
coming in and also when a client comes
in they have a life cycle they start
slow they will switch between production
over a period of time now what is
happening obviously we have been
delivering the same services to multiple
platforms like whatsapp notes
notifications to the system itself but
when we are building the super app what
we are making sure is that the platform
itself in a real-time basis morphs to
give that services in our real-time
clients to the different set of clients
like the first timers uh the traders and
also based on the life cycle very good
stage of the life they are and also
super app allows us to build multiple
services like you know we are planning
to go live with mutual fund eventually
insurance and other substrate services
which are seamless experience for a
client and we believe that in today's
platform this is done in a much more
you know a communication oriented way
you can move seamlessly into a real-time
process in super app where you can make
use this mix at the right time at the
right place which will allow customers
to have a great experience and actually
show the confidence of using an
experience services to the optimum level
with the services that they are coming
up with
as well
right now i i understand this and i
understand when you say that you know
the customer journey when it improves
and it becomes more seamless
a customer will engage will probably
engage more i just wanted to understand
how
how do we even how do we monitor this
just as an example a few examples that
you said
where you know
that there is a reporting system or the
reporting system is sort of lacking in
the current
uh current app and it will be much
better than the super app just need to
understand how do we monitor that our
customer has moved their business or
part of their business business
elsewhere sorry right so
yeah
through the super app just wanted to
understand that
but
uh obviously we have not uh you know we
don't see we have not seen clients who
have departed from our systems our
bounce rate is very low it's not even
it's less than five percent or something
it's where it's not even meaningful
right which means that once people come
to our platform they're staying on the
platform but that is not the same as
somebody who's staying on our platform
and spending the most that they can so
our problem is that they are not
spending the most that they can because
we ourselves are seeing drops in those
journeys so our product flows have
detailed metrics behind them and we have
studied this behavior over
over a period of time so we know that
you know these are the frustrating
points for the clients and this is
customer feedback that we have gotten
from surveys and stuff so we have 360
degree view and our own insight to
actually improve the journey and that's
what gives us the confidence that the
uh that uh that that this
database approach this data science
based approach will actually
lead us to the right end state you know
okay so so if i understand this
correctly and just to close the loop on
this what you are saying is that when a
customer is when we see a customer drop
off in the middle of our journey that is
how we understand that uh the customer
is not spending
as much as they could have on the app
because the journey is lacking somewhere
that is that the right understanding
absolutely very much like if you go to
amazon.com and if you're let's say if
you get stuck updating your profile page
odds are you're not going to go back
again
it's going to frustrate you right
we will not be able to quantify this but
this is a qualitative way of
understanding that
the customer is not spending as much as
they could
exactly exactly and this is what we have
spent a lot of time studying until then
its product team have lots and lots of
data about each and every journey where
we know where the customer is frustrated
what has gone wrong what can we do
better and the synthesis of whatever we
have understood is there in the super
accident that is really what how we uh
you know how we have built it you know
unless it's right here just a second the
second question uh and a more broader
question
if you look at overall industry edu is
uh
obviously largely driven by the fn or
derivative segment
and if you look at it over the last two
years it is almost more than quadrupled
like one of the participants also asked
earlier how do we understand the
sustainability of this uh this uh you
know trading volume or trading that is
happening currently and how should we
look at it over a more medium to long
term maybe right now we are seeing
elevated volumes because of various
reasons
but how do we extrapolate this to uh to
the medium than the long term
yeah so actually
you know dinesh uh dinesh is uh has
written a beautiful slide on this so i
would actually love for him to answer
this because he's the
best person
are you on the line yeah i saw my line
drop just can you just repeat that
question please
so the question is that uh over the last
couple of years we have seen adtos for
the industry grow significantly and
especially driven by the fno segment
now this has been driven because of
multiple reasons over the past two years
how should we look at the sustainability
of this and how should we extrapolate
this for the industry as a whole
over the medium to long term because in
the short term maybe this will sustain
uh but how should we look at it over the
long term
see what i believe is that we haven't
even like scratched the surface we are
just right now just capturing land
grabbing and uh getting customer in our
world but if you look at optimal kind of
unlike investment whether for the person
i should do an equity market i don't
think we have these there currently we
have like most of the customers are made
group of 20 28. so they have just
started their vocation they have started
their earning phase
so right now there is leveling equity
but i think serious rates of investment
will start
to come
so i don't believe what we saw is really
a peak i would say what we saw is just a
beginning
if you talk about market penetration
that indian is able to cover 98 percent
of pin code but you look at wallet share
that we are able to get in our market is
very minimum
so that's the reason we are actually uh
uh looking forward to super building a
content building journey so that we are
able to
increase lifetime value of a customer
that are on board so my answer would be
yet we haven't seen the best in this
industry in terms of
uh wallet share getting uh into our
market
looking at campaign like micro picture
where inflation rate is so low there's
no other option for a youth to get into
our market
so overall i feel that still that we are
yet to see a uh increase in wallet
shares today we are just talking about
market management account that we are
able to open
so just one small follow-up and that
will be my last question wanted to
understand from you
that again over this last couple of
years uh a lot of the market has also
been you know a lot of the new investors
that you spoke about
i've also made a lot of money
because of the run-up that we have seen
uh do we believe that these the
customers will remain sticky or will
continue to do the volumes that they are
doing currently
if we see a slum
or an elongated clamp not a not a you
know short-term slump
for a month or two but if you know if
it's an elongated from do you believe
that these customers will still remain
in the phone and continue to trade at
the level that they are today
we uh share a slide of this uh on uh
like impact of uh market volatility or
number of trades now that we are into
flat fee broking model so if you look at
number of trade even in times of like
movement brother crisis or when india
was facing big conference challenges
because of high inflation they never saw
a drop in number of trades so that is
really
like a true foreign traditional broker
when a ticket size of an order goes uh
smaller but for a player like us
customers who are active they remain
active what they do in that market is
that they reduce their ticket size
instead of like feeding one lakh car per
order they may trade maybe 50 000 per
hour
so overall i don't see any kind of like
trend going down in terms of number of
orders even the market has been cyclical
uh worst case was it even better prices
will not see declining number of click
on anything
so overall i believe as i said that we
are right now acquiring a new set of
customers who have no other option but
to put serious money in equity
now there is
i think this edu and participation from
perk uh investor is going to increase
from here
thank you
ladies and gentlemen this was the last
question for today i would now like to
hand the conference over to mr ganesh
tucker for closing comments
thank you everyone for joining us today
on this early call
india is now the part of achieving
long-term sustainable growth and this
growth will become a reality in an
inclusive and proliferated capital
market characterized by significant
penetration of equity
as highlighted earlier
india is gradually understanding the
benefit of arbitraging returns between
low risk assets and equities
according to a study done by deloitte
excess of smartphone will increase
significantly over the next five years
note of smartphone in river india will
be 2.4 x that of urban india
these are the realities of future growth
of intel companies like us
and the extent to which we prepare for
the presentation of the comprehensive
financial product suite for the
potential clients will position us ahead
of the competition by catering to an
evolving need of this untapped market
we will spare no effort in helping
investors achieve their goal while also
improving their overall investment
journey
we have successfully demonstrated the
implementation of our digital strategy
over the past few years and plan to
agree with the same as we move forward
to achieve our goal of obtaining a
leadership position in detailed working
industry in india
i am certain this goal is not too far
away i wish to thank you all for your
continued support and confidence in
angel one
for further queries please do reach out
to hitler buddha our head ir
or sva or investor relations advisors
i wish you all a
good day stay safe and stay strong thank
you
thank you
on behalf of angel one limited that
concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your life